

Caleb Mutuku

Date of birth: 02/09/1998 | **Nationality:** Kenyan | (+254) 748860959 |

calebkabaya7@gmail.com | https://github.com/CalebKabaya |

https://www.linkedin.com/in/caleb-kabaya/ Nairobi, Kenya

About me:

A motivated, passionate software engineering graduate with six months of experience in software development. With a high-energy approach, well-developed skills in Agile methodology, and driven to create user-focused web applications. I have developed several web apps including Awwards and Rated using Django framework for Python.

WORK EXPERIENCE

02/01/2022 - 17/07/2022 - Nairobi, Kenya

CODING BOOTCAMP - MORINGA SCHOOL

- I gained experience in Full Stack web development with Python/Django/Flask, AngularJS/Javascript, Html-5/Css3 stacks, and working with PostgreSQL/MYSQL database.
- Hosting web application on Heroku.
- Teamwork collaboration working with git and Github.
- Working with project management tools like Github, Trello, Asana, and Jira.

01/01/2020 - 30/03/2020 - Nairobi, Kenya

IT SUPPORT INTERN - KENYA FORESTRY RESEARCH INSTITUTE

- Supporting the IT team in maintaining hardware, software, and other systems.
- Assisting with troubleshooting issues and providing technical support.
- Organize and maintain IT resources.
- Software Installation.
- Assisting in web development and maintenance.
- Lend IT support in areas such as cybersecurity, programming, analytics, and data center management.

www.kefri.org

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

02/01/2022 - CURRENT - Nairobi, Kenya

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING - Moringa School

https://moringaschool.com/

07/05/2018 - 13/08/2021 - Nairobi, Kenya

DIPLOMA IN INFORMATION COMMUNICATION TECHNOLOGY – The Kabete National Polytechnic

kabetenationalpolytechnic.ac.ke

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): **ENGLISH**

Other language(s):

SWAHILI

DIGITAL SKILLS

My Digital Skills

Technical Skills

Intermediate JavaScript | Python | Framework Python Django e Flask | Heroku Cloud | Web: HTML, CSS | SQL (SQLite PostgreSQL MySQL) | Frontend: Angular 2+, AngularJS, jQuery, Bootstrap | GIT & Github | Trello, Asana

Soft-Skills

Experienced teamplayer | Emotional Intelligence - Empathy | High attention to detail. | Problems solving and decision making | Communication skills (listening skills; verbal skills; written skills) | Work Ethic | Critical and analytical thinking | Excellent time management

PROJECTS

Personal Gallery

https://github.com/CalebKabaya/Image--Gallery-

A personal gallery application to display various photos by categories and locations from around the world.

Awwards

https://github.com/CalebKabaya/Awwards

Awwards is an application that allows developers to post their projects and see how other developers rate them.

News Bloom

https://github.com/CalebKabaya/News-Bloom

This is a news application that lists and previews news articles from various sources by consuming the news API.

Rated

https://github.com/CalebKabaya/Rated

Rated is a web platform where employees can be able to rate their company in terms of the work environment they provide. This approach gives job seekers and employers what they've asked for - the freshest perspective on what it's really like to work inside any company, according to employee reviews.